Finding Aid for David Chudwin papers, 1968-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
David Chudwin papers 1968-1972
Chudwin, David
0.3 linear feet
861090 Aa 2
Reporter and editor of the Michigan Daily, student newspaper of the University of Michigan. Leaflets and newsletters collected relating to campus issues.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of David Chudwin (donor no. 5821 ) and came to the library in 1976.
The collection is open to research.
David Chudwin was a reporter and editor for the Michigan Daily, student newspaper of the University of Michigan.
The Chudwin papers consists of leaflets and newsletters collected relating to campus issues, especially concerning the protest over the war in Vietnam, the debate over the propriety of University classified research, the ecology movement, the Black Action Movement, and the activities of various radical groups. Also included are transcripts of interviews conducted on the issue of classified research.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Students--Political activity.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Demonstrations--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Collected Material
  - Black Action Movement, March 1970 (Box 1)
  - Radical Groups (Box 1)
    (e.g. SDS, White Panthers)
  - Black Panthers and other black groups (Box 1)
  - Tenants Union and Rent Strike (Box 1)
  - Welfare Mothers Demonstrations, September 1968 (Box 1)
  - Strike over proposed student bookstore, September 1969 (Box 1)
  - Vietnam War protest (Box 1)
  - St. Joseph Mercy Hospital controversy, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Enact Teach-in, April 1970 and Ecology (Box 1)
  - University issues (Box 1)
  - Classified Research Issue, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
- Transcripts of interviews
  - Re. classified research at the University of Michigan (Box 1)
    (include interviews with James T. Wilson, A. Geoffrey Norman, William Brown, and Thomas Butler)